2021: Outskirts of Tokyo
（爆発音）
（人々のざわめき）
（ざわめき）
（ガストレアの雄たけび）
（女の子）キャー！
A Gastrea!
（男性）ガストレアだ！
（男性）こっちに来るぞ！
It's heading this way!
（雄たけび）
Fire! Fire!
（兵士）撃て 撃て！
（ガストレアの悲鳴）
（人々の悲鳴）
（里見(さとみ)蓮太郎(れんたろう)）うわっ
（ガストレアの悲鳴）
（蓮太郎）ハァ…
（ガストレアの鳴き声）
（蓮太郎）はっ
ハァ ハァ…
（雄たけび）
If you do not want to die,
（天童菊之丞(てんどうきくのじょう)）
死にたくなければ―
survive, Rentaro.
生きろ 蓮太郎
♪～
～♪
10 Years Later:
Tokyo Area
（蓮太郎の荒い息遣い）
（蓮太郎）うっ…
#01 The Last Hope
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
What?
（多田島(ただしま)）ああん？
Permit
Tendo Civil Security Agency
Satomi Rentaro
You're the civil officer who's
come to help us out?
お前が 俺たちの応援に駆けつけた
民警だあ？
But you're still a kid.
ガキじゃねえか
I can't exactly help that,
but I'm the civil officer.
しかたねえだろ 俺が民警だよ
Tendo Civil Security Agency, huh...
（多田島）“天童民間警備会社”ね
Never heard of it.
聞かない名前だな
あっ
Hey, why don't we talk about work?
なあ 仕事の話 しねえか？
フンッ ４階だ
Fourth floor.
Someone on the floor below
下の階のヤツが
血の雨漏りがするって連絡してきた
reported that blood was leaking
through their ceiling.
Putting together all the information,
it's definitely a Gastrea.
情報を総合すると
間違いなく ガストレアだ
For cryin' out loud... Now that
you're here, I can finally go in.
やれやれ お前さんが来て
やっと入れるぜ
The law preventing you guys
from entering the scene
民警抜きで 現場に入るなってのは
without a civil officer is to
reduce the amount of victims.
あんたらの犠牲を減らすための
法律なんだぜ
That's exactly what I don't like about it!
だから 気に入らねえのさ
So, where's your partner, the "Initiator"?
お前 相棒のイニシエーターは
どうした？
（蓮太郎）ん…
As a standard, civil officers are supposed
to fight in pairs, aren't they?
民警の戦闘員は
２人１組で戦うのが基本だろ？
（藍原(あいはら)延珠(えんじゅ)）うわー！
I-I didn't think it was
necessary for her to help.
あ… あいつの手を
借りるまでもないと思ってな
Oh, Inspector.
（警官）あっ 警部！
Any changes?
何か変化は？
I-I'm sorry... two of our point men just went down
す… すみません
たった今 ポイントマンが２人
through the window with wires to engage.
懸垂降下して 窓から突入
We haven't heard from them since.
その後 連絡が途絶えました
Why didn't you wait for
the civil officer's arrival?
どうして 民警の到着を
待たなかった
We didn't want guys like
him to steal the glory!
こんなヤツらに―
手柄を横取りされたく
なかったんですよ
Out of the way. I'm going in!
どいてろ！
俺が突入する
You're rather late, Mr. Civil Officer.
（蛭子(ひるこ)影胤(かげたね)）
随分 遅かったじゃないか
民警くん
What...
なんだ… あんた 同業者か
Are you one of us?
I was, indeed, also after the Gastrea
that was the source of infection.
（影胤）私も
感染源ガストレアを追っていた
（蓮太郎）あっ
（影胤）が…
However,
I'm not one of you.
同業者ではない
なぜなら―
Because...
the one who killed these police officers...
この警官隊を殺したのは―
was me.
私だ
（蓮太郎）ふっ！
Not bad.
（影胤）なかなか やるね
（蓮太郎）うっ
ぐはっ
うっ！
うっ あ…
（携帯電話の着信音）
Is that you, Kohina?
（影胤）小比奈(こひな)か
Yes... Right.
ああ うん
I'll meet up with you in a moment.
これから 合流する
I will avenge my friends!
（警官）仲間の敵(かたき)だ！
うっ
Inzen: Kokutenfu!
隠禅(いんぜん)･黒天風(こくてんふう)
Inzen: Genmeika!
隠禅･玄明窩(げんめいか)
はっ
Oh, it's nothing. I'll be right there.
（影胤）いや なんでもない
すぐに そっちに行く
Splendid.
お見事
I didn't think you'd actually land a hit.
一撃もらうとは思わなかった
What is your name?
名前は？
Satomi Rentaro!
里見蓮太郎
Satomi-kun, eh?
（影胤）里見くんね
Let us meet again, Satomi-kun.
また どこかで会おう 里見くん
Just who are you?
あんた 何者だ？
I am...
（影胤）私は 世界を滅ぼす者
the one who will destroy the world.
It is impossible for anyone to stop me.
誰にも 私を止めることはできない
（蓮太郎）あっ
くっ…
Where's the Gastrea?
（多田島）ガストレアはどこだ？
The victims were assaulted here.
（蓮太郎）
ここで 被害者は襲われ―
Then they escaped through
the window in search of help.
そして 助けを求めて
和室の窓から逃げている
Come on, now...
おいおい 逃げるったって
ここはマンションの４階… あっ
You said "escaped," but this apartment
is on the fourth floo—
And if they were able to move
after losing this much blood...
しかも この出血で
動けるってことは…
So not only is the source of the infection
感染源どころか 感染者も
外をほっつき歩いてるのか！
running about, but the infected are, as well?
Pandemic...
（刑事）パンデミック…
Set a blockade around the
area, Inspector Tadashima!
周囲を封鎖してくれ
多田島警部！
Rentaro, you imbecile!
（延珠）蓮太郎の薄情者めー！
Regardless of the urgency, how dare he throw
me, his fiancée, off the bicycle and leave?!
急いでいたとはいえ
ふぃあんせの妾(わらわ)を
自転車から振り落とすとは
どういうことだ！
Little girl!
（岡島）お嬢ちゃん
うっ… なんの用だ？
What is it?! I am in quite a hurry!
妾は急いでおる！
はっ
Little girl... I wanted to ask for directions...
（岡島）お嬢ちゃん
道を聞きたいんだけど…
Do you... not understand
what is happening to you?
お主 自分がどうなっているのか
分かっていないのか？
Huh?
えっ？
There is nothing that I can do for you.
（延珠）妾には
どうしてやることもできない
Do you have any final words?
最後に何か
言い残すことはないのか？
あ…
あっ あっ ああ…
Do you remember now?
（延珠）思い出したか？
When I was on the balcony,
ベランダにいたとき
ガストレアに殺されかけて
I was almost killed by a Gastrea,
so I ran for my life...
必死で逃げて…
Sadly, I'm afraid that you will transition
from victim to aggressor very soon.
残念だが
お主は まもなく
被害者から加害者になってしまう
（岡島のうめき声）
H-Help me!
た… 助けてくれ
あっ！ うわっ なんだこれ
What is this?! It's all sticky!
ネバネバするぞ！
うわー！
Gastrea!
（蓮太郎）ガストレア！
Model Spider Stage One confirmed!
モデル･スパイダー
ステージⅠを確認！
I will now engage!
これより交戦に入る！
あ…
（多田島）うっ 何しやがる！
What d'ya think you're doing?!
Normal bullets have no effect on Gastrea!
ガストレアに通常の弾は
効果ねえんだよ！
It'll just agitate it more!
興奮させるだけだ！
（ガストレアの悲鳴）
It's working...
効いてる
Black bullets... Varanium!
黒い弾丸… バラニウム！
Yeah. It's a metal that stops
the regeneration of Gastrea!
ああ ガストレアの再生を
阻害する金属だ！
This one's a Stage One element,
こいつはステージⅠ単因子
a Jumping Spider Gastrea!
ハエトリグモのガストレアだ！
Damn it! I'm out of bullets.
クソッ 弾がない
（雄たけび）
（延珠）たーっ！
Enju!
（蓮太郎）延珠！
はーっ！
Hmph!
フンッ
You're too quick to let your guard down, Rentaro!
蓮太郎は すぐ油断するな
見ていられないぞ！
I can't bear to watch you!
I see... so this kid is...
そうか このガキが
Indeed. I am Rentaro's Initiator...
そうだ
妾こそ 蓮太郎のイニシエーター
もとい…
Or rather,
his partner,
相棒！ 藍原延珠だ！
Aihara Enju!
Don't you forget it, you public servant!
覚えておけ 公僕め！
More importantly, are you all right, Enju?
それより 大丈夫か？ 延珠
Yes. It'll heal soon.
ああ じきに治る
I'm more angered by the
destruction of my outfit.
妾は それより
ダメにされた服のほうが腹が立つ
The Cursed Children...
（多田島）呪われた子供たち…
What now? Are you smitten with me?
なんだ？ 妾にほれたのか？
Unfortunately for you, Rentaro and I
have sworn to be together forever.
残念だが 妾は蓮太郎と
将来を誓い合った仲だ
諦めろ
Give it up.
No one swore anything!
誰も誓い合ってねえよ！
What are you doing?!
何すんだよ!?
What? Did you want to do more, Rentaro?
なんだ もっとしたかったのか？
蓮太郎
You idiot!
アホ！
By the way, are you going to make it
in time for the limited time sale?
ところで タイムセールの時間は
いいのか？
えっ？ ああー！ ヤベッ
Oh... Crap!
Hey, you're leaving already?
おい もう行くのか？
Bean sprouts are six yen a bag!
（蓮太郎）
もやしが１袋６円なんだよ！
Rentaro, are you trying
to leave me behind again?
（延珠）蓮太郎！
また 妾を置いていくつもりか！
What happened earlier was inevitable!
（蓮太郎）
さっきのは不可抗力だろ！
How rude!
（延珠）ひどいヤツだ！
Varanium, huh?
バラニウムか…
Sir!
（刑事）警部！
うっ ひえ～
Initiators, born to fight Gastrea,
（多田島）
ガストレアと戦うべく生まれた
イニシエーター
and Promoters, who are in charge
of keeping them under control.
そして それを統率管理する
プロモーター
You mean that civil officer who was just here?
（刑事）さっきの民警ですか？
Yeah...
（多田島）ああ
They're humanity's last hope.
人類最後の希望さ
（２人）ハァ ハァ…
La La Loan
Tendo Civil Security Agency
Is there anything you'd like to
say before you die, Satomi-kun?
（天童木更(きさら)）死ぬ前に
何か言い残したいことはある？
里見くん
I-I can't do anything about
something that already happened.
す… 過ぎたことは
しょうがねえだろ
You idiot!
（立ち上がる音）
（木更）この おバカ！
（蓮太郎）うわっ！
Why did you run away?! You're infuriating!
なんで 逃げるのよ
腹立たしいわね！
Don't be ridiculous!
（蓮太郎）ムチャクチャ言うなよ！
So because you were in a rush to go
buy something at a limited time sale,
つまり 君は
タイムセールの商品を買うために
急いだら
you later realized that you forgot
to get compensation from the police?
警察から報酬をもらい損ねたことに
気がついたと…
You tried to contact them,
but they wouldn't pay you...
連絡したけど
警察に払ってもらえず
（蓮太郎）うん
And yet you bought two bags of bean sprouts.
それでも もやしは２袋
買ってきたと…
Very Delicious
Bean Sprouts
Would you like some, Kisara-san?
あんたも食べるか？ 木更さん
Tendo Civil Security Agency
President Tendo Kisara
Call me President while we're at work!
仕事しているときは
“社長”って言いなさい
ハァ…
Listen, Satomi-kun.
ちょっと 里見くん
今月は収入ゼロよ
We made nothing this month.
Whose fault do you think that is?
誰のせいだと思ってるの？
You're useless! A weakling! An idiot!
この かい性なし！
最弱！ おバカ！
And you actually gave the sale
priority over reporting to your boss?
それと 君の中では
社長への報告よりも―
タイムセールを優先させるの？
And most of all...
Why didn't you tell me about the sale?!
何より！
どうして 私にも
セールのことを
教えてくれなかったの？
（おなかが鳴る音）
Can't go on...
もうダメ…
ビフテキ 食べたい
I want steak...
So do I.
俺だって食べてえよ
Running a company is harder than I thought.
（木更）会社経営って
思ったより大変なのね
It's all because you're such
a useless idiot, Satomi-kun...
それもこれも 里見くんが―
かい性なしの おバカのせいね…
You're not going to blame it
on the company's location?
事務所の立地のせいじゃねえの？
Cabaret
Hana Ichi
If we were a better company,
the location wouldn't matter!
（木更）本当にいい会社なら
立地なんて関係ないのよ！
I know!
そうだ！
Why don't you put on a maid outfit
and hand out flyers, Kisara-san?
木更さんがメイド服とか着て
ビラを配りゃいい
Are you saying I should act like a hostess?
（木更）この私に
女給のマネをしろっていうの？
You need to run
里見くんが
into a crowd of people yelling,
"Tendo Civil Security Agency is right here!"
“天童民間警備会社 ここにあり”
って叫びながら
衆人環視の中
燃えるか爆発しなさい！
and catch on fire or explode!
That'd be an act of terrorism...
それじゃ テロだろ
（木更）ハァ…
Hey, the Gastrea you killed
was an infected, right?
ねえ 君が倒した
ガストレアって―
感染者だったのよね
Yeah. I didn't encounter the
source of the infection, though...
（蓮太郎）ああ
感染源には遭遇しなかったけど―
Some other company probably
already found it and got rid of it.
とっくに ほかの社が見つけて
始末してんだろ
Not only did no one take care of it,
駆除どころか―
No Hits
no one's even seen it.
目撃報告すら １件もないわ
Why didn't you send out a warning?
どうして 警報を出さない？
This is why we civil officers have our jobs.
だから 私ら民警に仕事があるのよ
Since it's not in the police's net,
it won't be easy to find.
警察の網にかかってないとなると
簡単には見つかりそうにないわね
I'll ask others in the business
if they know anything.
私も同業者に探りを入れてみる
Satomi-kun, we're going to hunt down
the other sources of infection, too!
里見くん 残る感染源も
私たちで狩るわよ！
Understood.
（蓮太郎）分かった
If you're going home, I'll walk you partway.
帰るなら ついでに送んぞ
I have a hemodialysis appointment today,
今日は 血液透析の日だから
病院に行かないと…
so I have to go to the hospital...
Oh... I see.
ああ… そうか
It's almost been an entire year...
（木更）そろそろ １年になるわね
since you became a Promoter
and met Enju-chan.
君がプロモーターになって
延珠ちゃんと出会ってから
It's only been a year.
（蓮太郎）まだ １年目だ
You and I are still only partway to our goals.
俺もあんたも
目的の半ばにすぎない
Satomi-kun, you've really changed lately.
里見くん
最近 本当に変わったわ
You smile a lot more.
よく笑うようになったもの
That's not true...
（蓮太郎）別に そんなことねえよ
So, what exactly is your current goal?
ねえ 君の今の目的って
なんなの？
You always said as a kid,
子供のころ よく言ったわよね
"I know Mom and Dad are alive,
so I'm going to find them."
お父さんとお母さんは―
必ず生きているから
捜し出すんだって
Do you still think that?
今でも 本当にそう思ってるの？
That has nothing to do with this.
（蓮太郎）関係ねえだろ
（木更）あ…
Stop bringing that up all the time!
いちいち うるせえんだよ あんた！
It doesn't matter anymore.
もういいんだ！
My parents died in that war!
俺の両親は
あの戦争で死んじまったんだ！
（ドアの開閉音）
ハァ…
Damn...
まいったな
I still can't handle it when
people bring up that subject...
相変わらず あの話をつつかれると
弱(よえ)えな 俺は…
It's already been ten years...
あれから もう10年だ
I need to build up a little tolerance already.
いいかげん 耐性つけないとな
（ドアが閉まる音）
Sensei, where are you?
先生 どこだよ？
Over here.
（室戸(むろと) 菫(すみれ)）ここだ
Whoa!
うわー！ あ…
（菫）フフフフ…
Boo!
バーッ
Don't scare me like that, Sensei!
驚かさないでくれよ 先生
Well, hello, Rentaro-kun.
やあ 蓮太郎くん
アビスへ ようこそ
Welcome to the abyss.
Corpses are great.
They don't waste time with idle chat.
死体はいいよ
無駄口きかないし
So, who's the guy?
（蓮太郎）誰だよ この男は
Charlie.
チャーリー　私の恋人だ
My boyfriend.
Wasn't it some woman named Susan before?
前は スーザンって女じゃ
なかったか？
The Gastrea you defeated earlier was
brought into our lab a little while ago...
君が倒したガストレアが
先ほど うちのラボに
運び込まれてきたよ
Can't you kill them a bit more cleanly?
もっと キレイに
倒せないものかな？
Not to mention there were bullets
lying all over the place...
おまけに 弾が
いろんな方向に散らばっている
Not only are you a perverted, lazy coward,
but you can't shoot worth a damn, either.
君は エッチで怠け者で
弱虫のうえに―
射撃の腕も悪い
Why haven't you killed yourself yet?
なんで まだ自殺してないんだ？
Am I that much of a lost cause?
そんなに絶望的なのかよ 俺は
If you don't shape up,
Kisara's never going to look your way.
いつまでも そんなじゃ
木更は振り向いてくれんぞ
Where'd that come from?!
うっ… なんで
そんな話になるんだよ！
If you like her, you should just
make her yours by force.
気になるなら 力ずくで
自分の所有物にしちまえば
いいのに
Kisara-san is a master of the
Tendo Martial Arts form of iaido...
木更さんは 天童式抜刀術っつう
居合の免許皆伝なんだよ
She'd kill me in an instant.
俺じゃ すぐに殺される
When you lived in the Tendo household,
（菫）君が天童家に
住んでたころ―
Kisara protected you from
her older brothers, right?
ほかの兄たちから
木更が守ってくれたんだっけか？
Yeah. I think I've gotten
ああ 今なら 俺も
strong enough to at least
protect Kisara-san now, too...
木更さんを守れるくらいには
強くなったと思うけど
But you're still as worthless as ever?
だが ヘタレなのは変わらず… か
（蓮太郎）うっ
Now let's get down to business.
（菫）さて 本題だ
You didn't come here to ask
about the autopsy, did you?
解剖所見を
聞きに来たわけでもあるまい？
Sensei, there are no reports
of eliminating or even spotting
（蓮太郎）先生
その感染源であるガストレアの―
the Gastrea that was the
source of the infection.
目撃報告も せん滅報告も
出てないんだ
At this rate, there'll be more victims.
このままじゃ 犠牲者が増える
Investigation, huh?
そうさねえ
Do you know the unique characteristic
of a jumping spider?
君は ハエトリグモの特徴を
知っているかね？
The color of its body, right?
特徴は体色だろ？
And it's known to jump when hunting its prey.
あと ジャンプして
獲物を捕るのは有名だな
Precisely...
そのとおり
By nature, even if an insect
grew to the size of a human,
本来 昆虫が
人間大になったからといって―
it would no longer be able
to use its jumping ability.
元のとおりの跳躍力を
示すことはない
Really?
（蓮太郎）そうなのか？
If a flea were to get that big,
（菫）
ノミが それほど巨大になれば―
it wouldn't be able to support its own body,
自分の体を支えられないし―
nor would it be able to breathe properly.
皮膚呼吸すら
満足にできないだろう
However, the Gastrea virus
turns all that around.
だが ガストレアウイルスは
全てを覆す
When an organism turns into a Gastrea,
生物がガストレアに
変化するとき―
the strength of its skin as
well as its physical functions
大きさに応じて強化された
皮膚の硬度―
are elevated to compensate for its size.
体機能の向上が起こる
The speed at which the Gastrea
virus is able to rewrite DNA
ガストレアウイルスがＤＮＡを
書き換えていく侵食スピードは
is irregular in every way.
あらゆる意味で規格外だ
And once it's taken over
more than 50% of the body,
そして 体内侵食率が
50％を超えると―
the body of the host can't
maintain its human form.
宿主は 人間の姿を
保てなくなり―
It goes through a process
in which its form is destroyed,
形象崩壊というプロセスを経て
ガストレアになる
and it becomes a Gastrea.
That process sometimes results
in new, original powers.
その過程で オリジナルの能力を
生み出す個体もある
The source you've yet to find
見つかっていない感染源も
may have acquired a new,
original power, as well.
何かオリジナルの能力を
得ているのかもしれないぞ
Like optical camouflage?
光学迷彩みたいな？
If it truly had that kind of ability,
本当に そんな能力を持っていたら
the Tokyo Area could become extinct
by a pandemic as early as tomorrow.
明日にでも 東京エリアは
パンデミックで壊滅するよ
It'll be okay.
大丈夫だ
Enju and I will make sure that won't happen...
それが起こらないように
俺と延珠が…
Enju-chan, huh?
延珠ちゃん！ ね～
Wh-What?
な… なんだ？
Your share.
君の分
あ…
You're not going to eat it?
食べないのかね？
あ…
Wow!
（延珠）うわ～！
Stir-fried bean sprouts,
もやし炒めに―
chilled bean sprouts in soy sauce,
もやしのお浸しに―
and bean sprout miso soup!
もやしのおみそ汁！
It all looks so delicious!
おいしそうだ
This is amazing, Rentaro.
すごいぞ 蓮太郎！
Hey, before you eat...
おい 食べる前に…
What? I've already passed along
the neighborhood bulletin.
なんだ？ 回覧板は回したぞ！
That's not what I'm talking about.
だから そうじゃなくて…
Oh! I see, Rentaro.
You want to do that thing.
ああ…
そうか 蓮太郎 あれがいいんだな！
Would you like dinner first, or your bath?
食事にする？ お風呂にする？
Or...
そ･れ･と･も
Hurry up and put some pants on!
さっさとパンツをはけー！
ハァ…
The meals you make are
so delicious, Rentaro.
蓮太郎の作るご飯は おいしいな
How can you make such delicious
meals from just bean sprouts?
なんで もやしだけから―
こんなに おいしいものが
作れるのだ？
Enju, it's time for your shot.
延珠 注射の時間だ
（延珠）うっ
All done.
（蓮太郎）終わったぞ
あ～ 日課も終わったなあ
Our daily routine is complete!
Now that we've filled our bellies,
there's only one thing left to do, Rentaro.
食欲を満たしたら
やることはもう
１つしかないだろ 蓮太郎
Yep. Goodnight.
（蓮太郎）うん おやすみ
むむむむ…
You insolent pig! How dare you ignore me?!
貴様！ 妾を無視するとは何事だ！
（蓮太郎）ん？
うわっ！
おりゃー！
（蓮太郎）うわー！
（延珠）こうしてやるー！
（ガラスが割れる音）
（蓮太郎）延珠！
うわっ… うわー！
（鳥のさえずり）
（２人の寝息）
Really now...
（延珠）まったく！
What kind of man are you,
passing up an offer from a lady?
淑女の誘いに乗らないとは
蓮太郎は なんなのだ！
Ladies are modest and prudent.
淑女ってのは 慎み深く思慮深い
Not to mention, you're as flat as a board.
そして お前の胸はペチャンコだ
Th-They'll get bigger soon enough!
うっ！
こ… これから大きくなる！
It's important to know when to give up.
人間 諦めが肝心なんだ
ぬがー！
However!
だが しかし
I hear there are many unfortunate people
世の中
大人の女性と恋愛できない
like yourself in the world who
cannot love mature women.
蓮太郎みたいな残念な人間も
多いと聞く
Things like, "Onii-chan,
inject Enju with your shot of love,"
“お兄ちゃん
延珠に 愛のお注射して”
are what you're into, right, Rentaro?
とか こんなのが大好きなんだろ？
蓮太郎は
I'm begging you, don't lead
me down the road to hell.
頼むから 俺を冥府魔道に
いざなうな
And eat your breakfast.
それから 朝飯 食え！
Okay!
はーい！
（人々の歓声）
Look! It's Seitenshi-sama!
（延珠）ん…
（レポーター）ご覧ください
聖天子(せいてんし)様です！
Seitenshi-sama has appeared on the balcony!
聖天子様がバルコニーに
お見えになりました
Tokyo Area Ruler: Seitenshi-sama
She has appeared alongside
her advisor, Tendo Kikunojo.
天童菊之丞補佐官と共に
お姿を見せました
Seitenshi's Advisor: Tendo Kikunojo
Hey, that's your...
（延珠）あっ
あれは 蓮太郎の…
Just hurry up and eat! Let's go, Enju!
早く食っちまえ
行くぞ 延珠
Say, Rentaro.
（延珠）なあ 蓮太郎
Why don't you take this opportunity
to transfer into my class?
この際だから
妾のクラスに編入してこないか？
Don't be ridiculous.
（蓮太郎）ムチャ言うな
Then keep failing school for the next six years,
じゃあ 妾が６年後
until I'm in my second year of high school.
高校２年生になるまで
留年して待ってろ！
There'd be quite a few problems with
a 23-year-old high school student....
23歳の高校生は
いろいろ ヤベえだろ
Enju, at school...
延珠 学校では…
Worry not.
大丈夫だ
No one has realized my true identity.
誰にも 妾のことはバレておらん
Morning, Enju-chan!
（舞(まい)）延珠ちゃん おはよー！
Morning indeed, Mai-chan.
おはようだ 舞ちゃん
I'm delighted to see that you're faring well.
壮健そうで何よりだ
I see you're talking weird as usual.
相変わらず 変なしゃべり方
Did you watch Tenchu Girls yesterday?
ねえ 昨日の
「天誅(てんちゅう)ガールズ」見た？
But of course.
もちろんだ
The nihilistic nature of
Tenchu Black, whom we are
敵か味方か
天誅ブラックのニヒルさは―
uncertain is friend or foe, is quite real.
本物だな
Yeah... but I think Tenchu Gold is cooler.
（舞）そうだね
でも 天誅ゴールドのほうが
カッコいいと思うな
Normally, the Gastrea virus is only spread
among humans through bodily fluids...
（菫）通常 人間に対して―
体液感染しかしないはずの
ガストレアウイルス…
But there are very rare cases in
which the Gastrea virus enters
だが ごくまれに―
妊婦の口から入った
ガストレアウイルスが―
the mouth of a pregnant woman,
infecting the offspring...
胎児に蓄積されて
生まれてくることがある
They are the Cursed Children.
それが“呪われた子供たち”だ
All of them are born girls.
生まれてきた子は 全員が女の子だ
Their eyes are red,
そして その目は赤く―
and the Gastrea virus is rooted
deep within their bodies.
体には ガストレアウイルスが
根を下ろしている
Because of the inhibiting
factor within their bodies,
抑制因子を持つ
その子たちの―
ウイルス侵食は
とても緩やかだが―
the virus's corrosion is very slow,
but there are quite a few
who refuse to accept
彼女たちを人間だと
認めない人々も―
that those children are human.
数多くいる
Ten years ago, humanity
was infected by Gastrea,
（蓮太郎）10年前
爆発的に蔓延(まんえん)した
寄生生物―
the parasitic lifeform that
spread like an explosion,
ガストレアによって
人類は感染され―
and we were nearly exterminated.
駆逐されていった
On the brink of extinction,
滅亡寸前だった人類は―
humanity surrounded itself with
giant Monoliths made from Varanium,
ガストレアが嫌う
バラニウム製の巨大な金属の塊―
a metal the Gastrea hated, and managed
to survive by staying within these barriers.
モノリスによって 結界を築き―
かろうじて
その内部に立てこもった
Ten years have passed.
以来 10年
After much trial and error,
人類は 試行錯誤を繰り返し―
humanity is gradually arming itself
with ways to fight Gastrea.
ガストレアと戦うすべを
身に着けつつある
At the core of that are Enju and the other
chosen Cursed Children, the Initiators.
その中心が―
呪われた子供たちから
選ばれた―
延珠たち
イニシエーターだ
Peace is being maintained here
thanks to those girls who inherited
ガストレアから
受け継いだ―
再生能力と
運動能力を持つ―
彼女たちによって―
Gastrea's regenerative and physical abilities.
このエリアの平安は
保たれている
The Cursed Children are indeed the
curse that Gastrea put upon humanity.
（菫）
呪われた子供たちは―
人類に
ガストレアがかけた―
呪いだ
However, they are also currently
the only thing that makes it possible
だが 人類が
ガストレアと―
戦うことを
可能にする―
for humanity to defeat Gastrea.
現在のところ
唯一の存在でもある
Those girls are the last hope for humanity.
彼女たちは
人類の最後の希望なんだよ
#02 The Mask of Madness
Why didn't you save them?
（延珠）なぜ 助けてやらなかった
（木更）仕事よ 里見くん
Time for work, Satomi-kun.
To the Ministry of Defense.
They're pointing their guns at us.
（木更）防衛省まで来て
（小比奈）鉄砲 こっちに向けてるよ
Despair.
Are you even human?
（影胤）絶望したまえ 諸君
（蓮太郎）お前 人間なのか？
The day of extinction is nigh.
（影胤）滅亡の日は近い